<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microservices - Go Lang</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/microservices/</guid>
      <description>What are microservices? The term &amp;ldquo;microservice&amp;rdquo; refers to a method of software development in which a large application is broken down into a set of smaller services that each operate in their own process and communicate with one another through application programming interfaces. Each microservice in an application is in charge of a single business function and may be built, deployed, and scaled independently. This method facilitates quicker application development and deployment in addition to increased adaptability, scalability, and resilience in complex applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RestAPI - Crud App</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/golang_rest_api_backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/golang_rest_api_backend/</guid>
      <description>Why Go? Go is regarded to be a strong option for backend development for a number of reasons.
Performance: Since Go is a compiled language, the resultant binary code is quick and efficient. Go was developed with performance in mind, making it an excellent option for creating high-performance backend systems.
Concurrency: Go&amp;rsquo;s built-in concurrency support enables developers to design code that is both efficient and scalable. Concurrent programming is vital for constructing contemporary backend systems, and goroutines and channels facilitate their creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archfire: Archlinux based linux distribution</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/archfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/archfire/</guid>
      <description>For my own usage, I created Archfire, a custom distribution based on Arch Linux. It comes with the pre-installed and pre-configured XFCE desktop environment. It provides the Calamares installer, which makes installing Arch Linux simple. Due to already installed drivers, it is already compatible with PCs that use Nvidia graphics. It includes my unique dotfiles for Neovim, Ranger, and Alacritty.
Download Archfire
Future goals: Adding multiple Desktop environments. Adding support for multiple hardwares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe Website</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/recipe_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/recipe_website/</guid>
      <description>Building a Django framework website to share recipes with foodies is a terrific way to show off one&amp;rsquo;s culinary chops. You can build a rich and user-friendly recipe website using Django&amp;rsquo;s strong and versatile framework, allowing users to effortlessly browse, search, and exchange recipes.
User registration and authentication, recipe development and administration, a recipe search and filter system, recipe categorization and tagging, user ratings and comments, and social media sharing are all elements that might be included into the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abhedya - The Cryptic Hunt</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/cryptic_hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/cryptic_hunt/</guid>
      <description>It is a FullStack website made in Django framework to conduct a event named Abhedya which is online cryptic hunt.
Features: Features like Login, Sign up, Forgot password, Email verification, etc . Celery to asynchronous sending of emails. Leader board to show the competitors about the results. Hunt Dashboard to manage users and eliminate any faulty entry. Link to the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews website - Django</title>
      <link>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/join.istenith.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sumitdhiman.in/projects/join.istenith.com/</guid>
      <description>It is a FullStack website made in Django framework to manage and ease the interviews procedure for society named ISTE-NITH.
Features: Form to submit CV and applications. Admin panel to manage the applicants. Excel and other formats of database exporting to help extracting the data. Media hosting of CVs. Dashboard for managers and admin. Graphs of data. UI/UX made to help user with application. Link to the project</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
