<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on </title>
    <link>http://sumitdhiman.live/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sumitdhiman.live/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recipe Website</title>
      <link>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/recipe_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/recipe_website/</guid>
      <description>Building a Django framework website to share recipes with foodies is a terrific way to show off one&amp;rsquo;s culinary chops. You can build a rich and user-friendly recipe website using Django&amp;rsquo;s strong and versatile framework, allowing users to effortlessly browse, search, and exchange recipes.
User registration and authentication, recipe development and administration, a recipe search and filter system, recipe categorization and tagging, user ratings and comments, and social media sharing are all elements that might be included into the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abhedya - The Cryptic Hunt</title>
      <link>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/cryptic_hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/cryptic_hunt/</guid>
      <description>It is a FullStack website made in Django framework to conduct a event named Abhedya which is online cryptic hunt.
Features: Features like Login, Sign up, Forgot password, Email verification, etc . Celery to asynchronous sending of emails. Leader board to show the competitors about the results. Hunt Dashboard to manage users and eliminate any faulty entry. Link to the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews website - Django</title>
      <link>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/join.istenith.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sumitdhiman.live/projects/join.istenith.com/</guid>
      <description>It is a FullStack website made in Django framework to manage and ease the interviews procedure for society named ISTE-NITH.
Features: Form to submit CV and applications. Admin panel to manage the applicants. Excel and other formats of database exporting to help extracting the data. Media hosting of CVs. Dashboard for managers and admin. Graphs of data. UI/UX made to help user with application. Link to the project</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
